Contact



+1 226-606-6590



orusaishtiaq@gmail.com



linkedin.com/orusa-akhtar



github.com/orusaish



orusaish.github.io

Technical Skills

JavaScript HTML CSS

Python Bash

Java

C# C/C++

Frameworks

Node.js

MongoDB

MySQL

Express

HandleBars

Sequelize

React

Firebase

Axios

JQuery

Git

Orusa Akhtar

Summary

A full stack web developer with a passion for front end web development and back end development. Enjoys working in a team environment and collaborating to create meaningful web applications. Certified in full stack web development from the University of Toronto and holding Masters in Computer Applications. Experienced in web development using the MERN stack and latest industry standards.

Projects

ParkEZ



- A web app that helps truckers and truck companies reserve and view parking spaces
- Built using React, Nodejs, Express, JavaScript, Sequelize, Passport, axios, bootstrap and MySQL

Train Scheduler





Built using moment.js, HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Bamazon





- An Amazon like storefront that helps maintain inventory and customer support
- Built using MySQL and Nodejs

Experience

Freelancing Web Developer

Jan 2019 - Present

Designing and developing web pages

Home Tutor 2006-2011

Tutored Math for middle and high school students

Math and Science Teacher

2004-2006

Taught math and science to grade 9 and 10 students in the International Indian School, Jeddah

Assistant Computer Science Professor

2002-2004

Sri Sathya Sai Arts and Science college, Bhopal India

- Taught data structures and database management systems
- Assisted students in programming assignments and debugging issues

Education

Full stack web development

University of Toronto, Mississauga

Master of Computer Application (MCA)

Samrat Ashok Technological Institute, Vidisha, India

Bachelor of Science (BSc)

Barkatullah University, Bhopal India